Abbas Wasim Efendi
Abd al-Wajid: Badr al-Din Abd al-Wajid [Wahid] ibn Muhammad ibn Muhammad al-Hanafi
Abhari: Athir al-Din al-Mufaddal ibn Umar ibn al-Mufaddal al-Samarqandi al-Abhari
Abi al-Fath al-Sufi
Abi al-Shukr
Abu al-Salt: Umayya ibn Abd al-Aziz ibn Abi Salt al-Dani al-Andalusi
Abu al-Uqul: Abu al-Uqul Muhammad ibn Ahmad al-Tabari
Abu Mashar Jafar ibn Muhammad ibn Umar al-Balkhi
Abubacer
Adami: Abu Ali al-Husayn ibn Muhammad al-Adami
Ahmad Mukhtar: Ghazi Ahmad Mukhtar Pasha
Albategnius
Albatenius
Albumasar
Albuzale
Alcabitius
Alfarabius
Alfonso X
Alfonso el Sabio
Alfonso the Learned
Alfonso the Wise
Alhazen
Ali al-Muwaqqit: Muslih al-Din Mustafa ibn Ali al-Qustantini al-Rumi al-Hanafi al-Muwaqqit
Ali ibn Isa al-Asturlabi
Ali ibn Khalaf: Abu al-Hasan ibn Ahmar al-Saydalani
Ali ibn Khalaf ibn Ahmar Akhir [Akhiyar]
Alpetragius
Amajur Family
Amili: Baha' al-Din Muhammad ibn Husayn al-Amili
Aryabhata I
Aryabhata II
Aryabhata the Elder
Aryabhata the Younger
Ashraf: al-Malik al-Ashraf (Mumahhid al-Din) Umar ibn Yusuf ibn Umar ibn Ali ibn Rasul
Avempace
Averroes
Avicenna
Azarquiel
Baha' al-Din Muhammad ibn Husayn al-Amili
Banu Musa
Bar Hiyya: Abraham Bar Hiyya Savasorda
Barhebraeus: Gregory Abu al-Faraj
Bastulus
Battani: Abu Abd Allah Muhammad ibn Jabir ibn Sinan Al-Battani al-Harrani al-Sabi'
Ben Solomon: Judah ben Solomon ha-Kohen
Birjandi: Abd al-Ali ibn Muhammad ibn Husayn al-Birjandi
Biruni: Abu al-Rayhan Muhammad ibn Ahmad al-Biruni
Bitruji: Nur al-Din Abu Ishaq [Abu Jafar] Ibrahim ibn Yusuf al-Bitruji
Buzjani: Abu al-Wafa' Muhammad ibn Muhammad ibn Yahya al-Buzjani
"Chioniades, Gregor [George]"
Cholgi: Mahmud Shah Cholgi
Costa ben Luca
Darandawi: Muhammad ibn Umar ibn Uthman al-Darandawi al-Hanafi
Dinakara
Don Profeit Tibbon
Dunash ibn Tamim
Farabi: Abu Nasr Muhammad ibn Muhammad ibn Tarkhan al-Farabi
Farghani: Abu al-Abbas Ahmad ibn Muhammad ibn Kathir al-Farghani
Farisi: Muhammad ibn Abi Bakr al-Farisi
Fazari: Muhammad ibn Ibrahim al-Fazari
Gersonides: Levi ben Gerson
"GÃ¶kmen, Mehmed Fatin"
Grigoriyos Bar Ebraya
Grigoriyos Bar Ebroyo
Habash al-Hasib: Abu Jafar Ahmad ibn Abd Allah al-Marwazi
Hajjaj ibn Yusuf ibn Matar
Harun al-Rashid
Hashimi: Ali ibn Sulayman al-Hashimi
"Husayn, Hasan and Muhammad"
Ibn Abi al-Fath al-Sufi: Shams al-Din Abu Abd Allah Muhammad ibn Abi al-Fath al-Sufi
Ibn Abi al-Shukr: Muhyi al-Milla wa-'l-Din Yahya Abu Abdallah ibn Muhammad ibn Abi al-Shukr al-Maghribi al-Andalusi [al-Qurtubi]
Ibn al-Adami: Muhammad ibn al-Husayn ibn Muhammad ibn Hamid
Ibn al-Alam: Ali ibn al-Husayn Abu al-Qasim al-Alawi al-Sharif al-Husayni
Ibn al-Banna': Abu al-Abbas Ahmad ibn Muhammad ibn Uthman al-Azdi al-Marrakushi
Ibn al-Ha'im: Abu Muhammad Abd al-Haqq al-Ghafiqi al-Ishbili
Ibn al-Haytham: Abu Ali al-Hasan ibn al-Hasan
Ibn al-Kammad: Abu Jafar Ahmad ibn Yusuf ibn al-Kammad
Ibn al-Majdi: Shihab al-Din Abu al-Abbas Ahmad ibn Rajab ibn Taybugha al-Majdi al-Shafii
Ibn al-Raqqam: Abu Abd Allah Muhammad ibn Ibrahim ibn Ali ibn Ahmad ibn Yusuf al-Mursi al-Andalusi al-Tunisi al-Awsi ibn al-Raqqam
Ibn al-Saffar: Abu al-Qasim Ahmad ibn Abd Allah ibn Umar al-Ghafiqi ibn al-Saffar al-Andalusi
Ibn al-Salah: Najm al-Din Abu al-Futuh Ahmad ibn Muhammad ibn al-Sari ibn al-Salah
Ibn al-Samh: Abu al-Qasim Asbagh ibn Muhammad ibn al-Samh al-Gharnati
Ibn al-Shatir: Ala' al-Din Ali ibn Ibrahim
Ibn Bajja: Abu Bakr Muhammad ibn Yahya ibn al-Sa'igh al-Tujibi al-Andalusi al-Saraqusti
Ibn Baso: Abu Ali al-Husayn ibn Abi Jafar Ahmad ibn Yusuf ibn Baso
Ibn Ezra: Abraham ibn Ezra
Ibn Iraq: Abu Nasr Mansur ibn Ali ibn Iraq
Ibn Ishaq: Abu al-Abbas ibn Ishaq al-Tamimi al-Tunisi
"Ibn Labban, Kushyar: Kiya Abu al-Hasan Kushyar ibn Labban Bashahri al-Jili (Gilani)"
Ibn Muadh: Abu Abd Allah Muhammad ibn Muadh al-Jayyani
Ibn Rushd: Abu al-Walid Muhammad ibn Ahmad ibn Muhammad ibn Rushd al-Hafid
Ibn Sahl: Abu Sad al-Ala' ibn Sahl
Ibn Sid: Isaac ibn Sid
Ibn Sina: Abu Ali al-Husayn ibn Abdallah ibn Sina
Ibn Tufayl: Abu Bakr Muhammad ibn Abd al-Malik ibn Muhammad ibn Muhammad ibn Tufayl al-Qaysi
Ibn Yunus: Abu al-Hasan Ali ibn Abd al-Rahman ibn Ahmad ibn Yunus al-Sadafi
Ibrahim ibn Sinan ibn Thabit ibn Qurra
Ikhwan al-Safa'
Isfizari: Abu Hatim al-Muzaffar ibn Ismail al-Isfizari
Ishaq ibn Hunayn: Abu Yaqub Ishaq ibn Hunayn ibn Ishaq al-Ibadi
Jabir ibn Aflah: Abu Muhammad Jabir ibn Aflah
Jacob ben Makhir ibn Tibbon
Jagannatha Samrat
Jaghmini: Sharaf al-Din Mahmud ibn Muhammad ibn Umar al-Jaghmini al-Khwarizmi
Jamal al-Din
Jawhari: al-Abbas ibn Said al-Jawhari
Jurjani: Ali ibn Muhammad ibn Ali al-Husayni al-Jurjani (al-Sayyid al-Sharif)
Juzjani: Abu Ubayd Abd al-Wahid ibn Muhammad al-Juzjani
Kamal al-Din al-Turkmani: Kamal al-Din Muhammad ibn Ahmad ibn Uthman ibn Ibrahim ibn Mustafa al-Maridini al-Turkmani al-Hanafi
Kamalakara
Kashi: Ghiyath (al-Milla wa-) al-Din Jamshid ibn Masud ibn Mahmud al-Kashi [al-Kashani]
Kesava
Khafri: Shams al-Din Muhammad ibn Ahmad al-Khafri al-Kashi
Khalifazade Ismail: Khalifazade Cinari Ismail Efendi ibn Mustafa
Khalili: Shams al-Din Abu Abdallah Muhammad ibn Muhammad al-Khalili
Khalji: Mahmud Shah Khalji
Kharaqi: Shams al-Din Abu Bakr Muhammad ibn Ahmad al-Kharaqi [al-Khiraqi]
al-Khatib al-Umawi al-Qurtubi
Khayyam: Ghiyath al-Din Abu al-Fath Umar ibn Ibrahim al-Khayyami al-Nishapuri
Khazin: Abu Jafar Muhammad ibn al-Husayn al-Khazin al-Khurasani
"Khazini: Abu al-Fath Abd al-Rahman al-Khazini (Abu Mansur Abd al-Rahman, Abd al-Rahman Mansur)"
Khujandi: Abu Mahmud Hamid ibn al-Khidr al-Khujandi
Khwarizmi: Muhammad ibn Musa al-Khwarizmi
Kindi: Abu Yusuf Yaqub ibn Ishaq al-Kindi
Kuhi: Abu Sahl Wijan ibn Rustam [Wustam] al-Kuhi [al-Quhi]
Kushyar ibn Labban: Kiya Abu al-Hasan Kushyar ibn Labban Bashahri al-Jili (Gilani)
Lari: Muslih al-Din Muhammad ibn Salah ibn Jalal al-Sadi al-Ibadi al-Ansari al-Lari
Maimonides: Abu Imran Musa [Moses] ibn Ubayd Allah [Maymun] al-Qurtubi
Majriti: Abu al-Qasim Maslama ibn Ahmad al-Hasib al-Faradi al-Majriti
Manjula
Marrakushi: Sharaf al-Din Abu Ali al-Hasan ibn Ali ibn Umar al-Marrakushi
Marwarrudhi: Khalid ibn Abd al-Malik al-Marwarrudhi
Masha'allah ibn Athari (Sariya)
Ma'mun: Abu al-Abbas Abdallah ibn Harun al-Rashid
Mathuranatha Sarman
Messahala
"Metochites [Metoxites], Theodore [Theodoros, Theoleptos]"
Miram Celebi: Mahmud ibn Qutb al-Din Muhammad ibn Muhammad ibn Musa Qadizade
Mizzi: Zayn al-Din [Shams al-Din] Abu Abd Allah Muhammad ibn Ahmad ibn Abd al-Rahim al-Mizzi al-Hanafi
Munjala
Najm al-Din al-Misri: Najm al-Din Abu Abd Allah Muhammad ibn Muhammad ibn Ibrahim al-Misri
Nasawi: Abu al-Hasan Ali ibn Ahmad al-Nasawi
Nastulus: Muhammad ibn Abd Allah
Nayrizi: Abu al-Abbas al-Fadl ibn Hatim al-Nayrizi
Nisaburi: al-Hasan ibn Muhammad ibn al-Husayn Nizam al-Din al-Araj al-Nisaburi
Omar Khayyam
Paramesvara of Vatesseri [Paramesvara I]
Profatius
Qabisi: Abu Saqr Abd al-Aziz ibn Uthman ibn Ali al-Qabisi
Qadizade al-Rumi: Salah al-Din Musa ibn Muhammad ibn Mahmud al-Rumi
Qattan al-Marwazi: Ain al-Zaman Abu Ali Hasan ibn Ali Qattan al-Marwazi
Qasim ibn Mutarrif al-Qattan: Abu Muhammad Qasim ibn Mutarrif ibn Abd al-Rahman al-Qattan al-Tulaytuli al-Qurtubi al-Andalusi
Qunawi: Muhammad ibn al-Katib Sinan al-Qunawi
Qushji: Abu al-Qasim Ala' al-Din Ali ibn Muhammad Qushci-zade
Qusta ibn Luqa al-Balabakki
Raghavananda Sarman
Ridwan al-Falaki: Ridwan Efendi ibn Abdallah al-Razzaz al-Falaki
Rudani: Abu Abdallah Muhammad ibn Sulayman (Muhammad) al-Fasi ibn Tahir al-Rudani al-Susi al-Maliki [al-Maghribi]
Sadr al-Sharia al-Thani: Ubaydallah ibn al-Masud al-Mahbubi al-Bukhari al-Hanafi
Saghani: Abu Hamid Ahmad ibn Muhammad al-Saghani al-Asturlabi
Said al-Andalusi: Abu al-Qasim Said ibn abi al-Walid Ahmad ibn Abd al-Rahman ibn Muhammad ibn Said al-Taghlibi al-Qurtubi
Salih Zeki
Samarqandi: Shams al-Din Muhammad ibn Ashraf al-Husayni al-Samarqandi
Samaw'al: Abu Nasr Samaw'al ibn Yahya ibn Abbas al-Maghribi al-Andalusi
Sanad ibn Ali: Abu al-Tayyib Sanad ibn Ali al-Yahudi
"Severus Sebokht [Sebokt, Sebukht, Seboht]"
Shams al-Din al-Bukhari
Sharaf al-Din al-Tusi
Shirazi: Qutb al-Din Mahmud ibn Masud Muslih al-Shirazi
Shirwani: Fathallah ibn Abu Yazid ibn Abd al-Aziz ibn Ibrahim al-Shabarani al-Shirwani al-Shamahi
Sibt al-Maridini: Muhammad ibn Muhammad ibn Ahmad Abu Abd Allah Badr [Shams] al-Din al-Misri al-Dimashqi
Sijzi: Abu Said Ahmad ibn Muhammad ibn Abd al-Jalil al-Sijzi
Sufi: Abu al-Husayn Abd al-Rahman ibn Umar al-Sufi
Sulayman ibn Isma: Abu Dawud Sulayman ibn Isma al-Samarqandi
Suyuti: Abu al-Fadl Abd al-Rahman Jalal al-Din al-Suyuti
Tabari: Abu Jafar Muhammad ibn Ayyub al-Hasib al-Tabari
Taqi al-Din Abu Bakr Muhammad ibn Zayn al-Din Maruf al-Dimashqi al-Hanafi
Tezkireci Köse Ibrahim
Thabit ibn Qurra
Tusi: Abu Jafar Muhammad ibn Muhammad ibn al-Hasan Nasir al-Din al-Tusi
Ubaydi: Jalal al-Din Fadl Allah al-Ubaydi
Ulugh Beg: Muhammad Taraghay ibn Shahrukh ibn Timur
Umawi: Abu Ali al-Hasan ibn Ali ibn Khalaf al-Umawi
Urdi: Mu'ayyad (al-Milla wa-) al-Din (Mu'ayyad ibn Barik [Burayk]) al-Urdi (al-Amiri al-Dimashqi)
Utarid: Utarid ibn Muhammad al-Hasib
Wabkanawi: Shams al-Munajjim [Shams al-Din] Muhammad ibn Ali Khwaja al-Wabkanawi [Wabkanawi]
Yahya ibn Abi Mansur: Abu Ali Yahya ibn Abi Mansur al-Munajjim
Yaqub ibn Tariq
Yativrsabha
Yavanesvara
Zacut: Abraham ben Samuel Zacut
Zarqali: Abu Ishaq Ibrahim ibn Yahya al-Naqqash al-Tujibi al-Zarqali
Zhamaluding: Jamal al-Din Muhammad ibn Tahir ibn Muhammad al-Zaydi al-Bukhari